export const eQUESTIONS= [
    {id:1, question: `<p><strong><em>Mark the letter A, B, C or D on your answer sheet to indicate the word whose underlined part differs from the other three in pronunciation in each of the following questions.</em></strong></p>
      <p><strong>Question 1:</strong></p>`, 
      options:[
        `<p><strong>A.</strong> s<u>ou</u>nd </p>`,
        `<p><strong>B.</strong> <u>ou</u>t    </p>`,
        `<p><strong>C.</strong> f<u>ou</u>nd </p>`,
        `<p><strong>D.</strong> en<u>ou</u>gh</p>`
      ],
      answer:4,
      explanation:`<strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>A. s<u>ou</u>nd /saʊnd/     </p><p>B. <u>ou</u>t /aʊt/</p><p>C. f<u>ou</u>nd /faʊnd/     </p><p>D. en<u>ou</u>gh /ɪˈnʌf/</p><p>Phần gạch chân đáp án D được phát âm là /ʌ/, còn lại được phát âm là /aʊ/.</p><p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p><p>` },

    {id:2, 
      question: `<p><strong>Question 2:</strong></p>
      `, 
      options:[
        `<p><strong>A.</strong> work<u>ed</u> </p>`, 
        `<p><strong>B.</strong> watch<u>ed </u></p>`, 
        `<p><strong>C.</strong> relax<u>ed</u>  </p>`, 
        `<p><strong>D.</strong> crowd<u>ed</u></p>`],
      answer:4,
      explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Phát âm “-ed”</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>A. work<u>ed</u> /wɜːkt/       </p><p>B. watch<u>ed</u> /wɒtʃt/</p><p>C. relax<u>ed</u> /rɪˈlækst/      </p><p>D. crowd<u>ed</u> /ˈkraʊdɪd/</p><p><strong>Quy tắc: </strong>Cách phát âm đuôi “-ed”:<strong></strong></p><p>- /t/: khi động từ có phát âm kết thúc là /s/, /f/, /p/, /ʃ/, /tʃ/, /k/ và /s/.</p><p>- /id/: khi động từ có phát âm kết thúc là /t/ hay /d/</p><p>- /d/: với những trường hợp còn lại</p><p>Phần gạch chân đáp án D được phát âm là /ɪd/, còn lại được phát âm là /t/.</p><p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p>` },
    {id:3, 
        question: `<p><strong><em>Mark the letter A, B, C or D on your answer sheet to indicate the word that differs from the other three in the position of primary stress in each of the following questions.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Question 3:</strong></p>
        `, 
        options:[
          `<p><strong>A.</strong><strong> </strong>leisure </p>`, 
          `<p><strong>B.</strong> diving </p>`, 
          `<p><strong>C.</strong> origami </p>`,
          `<p><strong>D. </strong>movie</p>`],
        answer:3,
        explanation:`<p><strong>3. C</strong></p><p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Trọng âm từ có 2, 4 âm tiết</p>

<p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>A. leisure /ˈleʒə/    </p><p>B. diving /ˈdaɪvɪŋ/</p><p>C. origami /ɒrɪˈɡɑːmi/    </p><p>D. movie /ˈmuːvi/</p><p><strong>Quy tắc:</strong></p><p>- Động từ thường có trọng âm rơi vào âm tiết thứ hai.</p><p>- Danh từ, tính từ thường có trọng âm rơi vào âm thứ nhất.</p><p>Trọng âm đáp án C rơi vào âm tiết thứ ba, còn lại là âm thứ nhất.</p><p><strong>Chọn C.</strong></p>` },
    {id:4, 
      question: `<p><strong>Question 4:</strong></p>`, 
      options:[
        `<p><strong>A.</strong> ancestor </p>`, 
        `<p><strong>B.</strong> curious </p>`, 
        `<p><strong>C.</strong> heritage </p>`,
        `<p><strong>D.</strong> tradition</p>`],
      answer:4,
      explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Trọng âm từ có 3 âm tiết</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>A. ancestor /ˈænsestə/    </p>

<p>B. curious /ˈkjʊəriəs/ </p><p>C. heritage /ˈherɪtɪdʒ/    </p><p>D. tradition /trəˈdɪʃn/</p><p><strong>Quy tắc:</strong> Những từ có tận cùng là đuôi “-ious”, “-ion” có trọng âm rơi vào âm tiết đứng ngay trước nó.</p><p>Trọng âm đáp án D rơi vào âm tiết thứ hai, còn lại là âm thứ nhất.</p><p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p>` },
    {id:5, 
        question: `<p><strong><em>Mark the letter A, B, C or D on your answer sheet to indicate the underlined part that needs correction in each of the following questions.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Question 5:</strong> She is <u>boring with</u> the silent <u>surrounding</u> because she <u>used</u> to <u>live</u> in a big city.</p>
        `, 
        options:[
          `<strong>A.</strong>  <u>boring with</u>`, 
          `<strong>B.</strong> <u>surrounding</u>`, 
          `<strong>C.</strong> <u>used</u>`,
          `<strong>D.</strong> <u>live</u>`],
        answer:1,
        explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Tình từ</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>Phân biệt tính từ đuôi “-ing” và “-ed”:</p><p>- Tính từ đuôi “-ing”: dùng để miêu tả tính cách, tính chất, đặc điểm của người, sự vật, hiện tượng.</p>

<p>- Tính từ đuôi “-ed”: dùng để diễn tả cảm xúc, cảm nhận của con người, con vật về một sự vật, hiện tượng, sự việc nào đó.</p><p>Sửa: boring =&gt; bored</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Cô ấy chán cảnh tĩnh lặng xung quanh vì cô ấy từng sống ở một thành phố lớn.</p><p><strong>Chọn A.</strong></p>` },
    {id:6, 
      question: `<p><strong>Question 6:</strong> <u>The Muong</u> people are <u>the ethnic</u> minority who live <u>in the</u> mountainous regions <u>of Vietnam</u>.</p>
      `, 
      options:[`<strong>A.</strong> <u>The Muong</u>`, 
        `<strong>B.</strong> <u>the ethnic</u>`, 
        `<strong>C.</strong> <u>in the</u>`,
        `<strong>D.</strong> <u>of Vietnam</u>`],
      answer:2,
      explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Mạo từ</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>Mạo từ “a/an” được dùng với danh từ đếm được số ít được nhắc đến lần đầu hoặc chưa được xác định.</p><p>Sửa: the ethnic =&gt; an ethnic</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Người Mường là một dân tộc thiểu số sống ở các vùng miền núi Việt Nam.</p>

<p><strong>Chọn B.</strong></p>` },
  {id:7, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 7:</strong> There <u>used to</u> be a movie theater here <u>but</u> it <u>closes</u> <u>a</u> long time ago.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<strong>A.</strong> <u>used to</u>`, 
      `<strong>B.</strong> <u>but</u>`,
      `<strong>C.</strong> <u>closes</u>`,
      `<strong>D.</strong> <u>a</u>` 
     ],
    answer:3,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Thì quá khứ đơn</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>Thì quá khứ đơn dùng để diễn tả một hành động đã xảy ra và kết thúc trong quá khứ.</p><p>Công thức: S + Ved.</p><p>Dấu hiệu: “a long time ago” (lâu lắm rồi)</p><p>Sửa: closes =&gt; closed</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Ở đây từng có rạp chiếu phim nhưng đóng cửa lâu rồi.</p><p><strong>Chọn C.</strong></p>` },
  {id:8, 
      question: `<p><strong><em>Mark the letter A, B, C or D on your answer sheet to indicate the correct answer to each of the following questions.</em></strong><strong><em></em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Question 8:</strong> Life in a small town is __________ than that in a big city</p>
      `, 
      options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> peaceful </p>`, 
        `<p><strong>B.</strong> much peaceful</p>`, `<p><strong>C.</strong> less peaceful </p>`,`<p><strong>D.</strong> much more peaceful</p>`],
      answer:4,
      explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>So sánh hơn/ kém</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>So sánh hơn/ kém với tính từ dài: S + to be + (much) more/ less adj + than + N/Pronoun.</p>

<p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Cuộc sống ở một thị trấn nhỏ yên bình hơn nhiều so với ở thành phố lớn.</p><p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p>` },
  {id:9,
    question: `<p><strong>Question 9:</strong> month is the Hoa Ban Festival of the Thai people held in?</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> When </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> Which </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> How many </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> How often</p>`],
    answer:2,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ nghi vấn</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>A. When: khi nào     </p><p>B. Which: cái nào (ngụ ý lựa chọn)</p><p>C. How many: bao nhiêu    </p><p>D. How often: bao nhiêu lần (hỏi về tần suất)</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Lễ hội Hoa Ban của dân tộc Thái được tổ chức vào tháng mấy?</p><p><strong>Chọn B.</strong></p>` },
  {id:10, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 10:</strong> The Gong Festival is held __________ in the Central Highlands.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> year </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> yearly </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> annual </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> annually</p>`],
    answer:4,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ vựng</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p>

<p>A. year (n): năm</p><p>B. yearly (adj/adv): hằng năm, thường niên (năm nào cũng có, từ 1 lần trở lên)</p><p>C. annual (adj): hàng năm</p><p>D. annually (adj): hàng năm (mỗi năm một lần)</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Lễ hội Cồng Chiêng được tổ chức hàng năm ở Tây Nguyên.</p><p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:11, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 11:</strong> What colour is ________ symbol of good luck for the Hoa?</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> a </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> an  </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> Ø </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> some</p>`],
    answer:1,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Mạo từ</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>Mạo từ “a/an” được dùng với danh từ đếm được số ít được nhắc đến lần đầu hoặc chưa được xác định.</p>

<p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Màu gì tượng trưng cho sự may mắn đối với người mệnh Hỏa?<strong></strong></p><p><strong>Chọn A.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:12, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 12:</strong> "Do you love it?" can be abbreviated:</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> WBU </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> J4F </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> NUFF </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> DYLI</p>`],
    answer:4,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ vựng</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>Cụm từ sẽ được viết tắt theo chữ cái đầu, và chữ cái đó phải viết in hoa.</p><p>"Yêu thích nó không?" có thể được viết tắt:</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>"Yêu thích nó không?" có thể được viết tắt: DYLI.</p><p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:13, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 13:</strong> Steven dislikes _______, so he usually takes a bus to work.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> to drive </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> to be driven </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> be driven</p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> driving</p>`],
    answer:4,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>to V/Ving</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>dislike + V-ing: không thích làm gì</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Steven không thích lái xe, vì vậy anh thường đi xe buýt đến nơi làm việc.</p>

<p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:14, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 14:</strong> I think country life is so boring and _______ because you’re not close to shops and services.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> unhealthy</p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> inconvenient </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> comfortable </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> peaceful</p>`],
    answer:2,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ vựng</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>A. unhealthy (adj): không lành mạnh </p><p>B. inconvenient (adj): bất tiện</p><p>C. comfortable (adj): thoải mái    </p><p>D. peaceful (adj): yên bình</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Tôi nghĩ cuộc sống nông thôn thật buồn tẻ và bất tiện vì bạn không ở gần các cửa hàng và dịch vụ.</p><p><strong>Chọn B.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:15, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 15:</strong> Visitors find the Central Highland_______.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> attraction </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> attractive </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> attract </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> attractively</p>`],
    answer:2,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ loại</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>A. attraction (n): sự hấp dẫn   </p><p>B. attractive (adv): thu hút, hấp dẫn</p>

<p>C. attract (v): thu hút, hấp dẫn   </p><p>D. attractively (adv): thu hút, hấp dẫn</p><p>=&gt; find st adj: thấy cái gì như thế nào</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Du khách thấy Tây Nguyên hấp dẫn.</p><p><strong>Chọn B.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:16, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 16: </strong>Farmers who are working on _______ look very happy with shining smiles in summer days.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> grasslands  </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> paddy fields </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> factories </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> construction sites</p>`],
    answer:2,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ vựng</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>A. grasslands (n): đồng cỏ   </p><p>B. paddy fields (n): cánh đồng lúa</p><p>C. factories (n): nhà máy   </p><p>D. construction sites (n): công trường</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Những người nông dân đang làm việc trên cánh đồng lúa trông rất vui với nụ cười rạng rỡ trong những ngày hè.</p>

<p><strong>Chọn B.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:17, 
    question: `<p><strong><em>Mark the letter A, B, C or D on your answer sheet to indicate the most suitable response to complete each of the following exchanges. </em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Question 17:</strong> - ‘I have two tickets to a gong performance. Would you like to go?’</p>
<p>- ‘_________ What time?’</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> Sorry, I can’t.</p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> Not very good. </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> Yes, I’d like that. </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> Never mind.</p>`],
    answer:3,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Ngôn ngữ giao tiếp</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>‘Tôi có hai vé xem một buổi biểu diễn cồng chiêng. Bạn có muốn đi không? '</p><p>- '_________. Mấy giờ thế?'</p><p>A. Xin lỗi, tôi không thể.     </p><p>B. Không tốt lắm.</p><p>C. Vâng, tôi thích điều đó.   </p><p>D. Đừng bận tâm.<strong> </strong></p><p>Các phản hồi A, B, D không phù hợp với ngữ cảnh.</p><p><strong>Chọn C.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:18, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 18:</strong> - ‘Is it true that Y Moan was the greatest pop singer of the Ede?’</p>
<p>- ‘_________’.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> Really?  </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> How beautiful! </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> Come on! </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> Exactly.</p>`],
    answer:4,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Ngôn ngữ giao tiếp</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>‘Có phải Y Moan là ca sĩ hát bội vĩ đại nhất của người Êđê không? ”</p>

<p>- ‘_________’.</p><p>A. Thật không?      </p><p>B. Đẹp làm sao!</p><p>C. Đi thôi!      </p><p>D. Chính xác.</p><p>Các phản hồi A, B, C không phù hợp với ngữ cảnh.</p><p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:19, 
    question: `<p><strong><em>Mark the letter A, B, C or D on your answer sheet to indicate the word(s) CLOSEST in meaning to the underlined word(s) in each of the following questions. </em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Question 19: </strong>He was late, but <strong><u>fortunately</u></strong> his friends waited for him.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> luckily </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> magically </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> cruelly </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> lately</p>`],
    answer:1,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ đồng nghĩa</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>fortunately (adv): may mắn</p><p>A. luckily (adv): may mắn    </p><p>B. magically (adv): kỳ diệu</p><p>C. cruelly (adv): tàn nhẫn    </p><p>D. lately (adv): gần đây</p>

<p>=&gt; fortunately (adv) = luckily (adv): may mắn</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Anh ấy đến muộn, nhưng may mắn thay bạn bè của anh ấy đã đợi anh ấy.</p><p><strong>Chọn A.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:20, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 20:</strong> Will she be <strong><u>annoyed</u></strong><u> </u>that you forgot to phone?</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> displeased</p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> pleased </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> please</p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> pleasure</p>`],
    answer:1,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ đồng nghĩa</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>annoyed (adj): khó chịu</p><p>A. displeased (adj): không hài lòng </p><p>B. pleased (adj): hài lòng, vui mừng</p><p>C. please (v): làm vui lòng   </p><p>D. pleasure (n): niềm vui</p><p>=&gt; annoyed (adj): khó chịu = displeased (adj): không hài lòng</p>

<p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Cô ấy sẽ khó chịu vì bạn quên điện thoại đúng không?</p><p><strong>Chọn A.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:21, 
    question: `<p><strong><em>Mark the letter A, B, C or D on your answer sheet to indicate the word(s) OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word(s) in each of the following questions. </em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Question 21:</strong> Mr Thompson works more <strong><u>carefully</u></strong> than Mr Baker.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> carelessly </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> carefully</p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> carefulness  </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> uncarefully</p>`],
    answer:1,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ trái nghĩa</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>carefully (adv): cẩn thận</p><p>A. carelessly (adv): bất cẩn  </p><p>B. carefully (adv): cẩn thận</p><p>C. carefulness (n): sự bất cẩn   </p><p>D. uncarefully: từ không tồn tại</p><p>=&gt; carefully (adv): cẩn thận &gt;&lt; carelessly (adv): bất cẩn</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Ông Thompson làm việc cẩn thận hơn ông Baker.</p>

<p><strong>Chọn A.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:22, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 22:</strong> I like providing <strong><u>minority</u></strong> children with literacy</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> adult </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> most </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> majority </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> many</p>`],
    answer:3,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ trái nghĩa</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>minority (n): thiểu số</p><p>A. adult (n): người lớn     </p><p>B. most: hầu hết</p><p>C. majority (n): đa số     </p><p>D. many: nhiều</p><p>=&gt; minority (n): thiểu số &gt;&lt; majority (n): đa số</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Tôi thích dạy trẻ em thiểu số học chữ.</p><p><strong>Chọn C.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:23, 
    question: `<p><strong><em>Read the following passage and mark the letter A, B, C, or D on your answer sheet to indicate the correct word or phrase that best fits each of the numbered blanks.</em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Viet is a student and he (23) ______ in a bed-sit in a suburb of Ha Noi. It is a part of an old house. He has one room and a kitchen and (24) ______ a bathroom with three other people. In his room, there is a bed on the left hand side. There is (25) _______ armchair beside the bed. The desk is opposite the bed and there is a closet (26) ______ the right side of the room. Above the desk, there is a bookshelf and above the bed there is a clock. He has a TV and a cassette player. The room is rather (27) ______, but it’s OK. Viet likes this room very much.</p>
<p><strong>Question 23:</strong></p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> lives </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> live </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> will live </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> is going to live</p>`],
    answer:1,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Thì hiện tại đơn</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>Thì hiện tại đơn diễn tả một hành động hay sự việc mang tính chất chung chung, tổng quát lặp đi lặp lại nhiều lần hoặc một sự thật hiển nhiên hay một hành động diễn ra trong thời gian ở hiện tại.</p>

<p>Công thức: S + V(s/es).</p><p>Dấu hiệu: “he” (anh ấy) là chủ ngữ ngôi 3 số ít =&gt; động từ chia ở dạng số ít</p><p>Viet is a student and he <strong>(23) <u>lives</u></strong> in a bed-sit in a suburb of Ha Noi.</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Việt là sinh viên và anh ấy đang sống trong một căn phòng tại ngoại thành Hà Nội.</p><p><strong>Chọn A.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:24, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 24:</strong></p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> shares</p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> has </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> puts </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> takes</p>`],
    answer:1,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ vựng</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>A. shares (v): chia sẻ    </p><p>B. has (v): có</p><p>C. puts (v): đặt, để     </p>

<p>D. takes (v): cầm, lấy</p><p>He has one room and a kitchen and <strong>(24) <u>shares</u></strong> a bathroom with three other people.</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Anh ấy có một phòng và một nhà bếp và dùng chung phòng tắm với ba người khác.</p><p><strong>Chọn A.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:25, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 25:</strong></p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> an </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> a </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> some </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> the</p>`],
    answer:1,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Mạo từ</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>Mạo từ “a/an” được dùng với danh từ đếm được số ít được nhắc đến lần đầu hoặc chưa được xác định.</p><p>There is <strong>(25) <u>an</u></strong> armchair beside the bed.</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Có một chiếc ghế bành bên cạnh giường.</p>

<p><strong>Chọn A.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:26, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 26:</strong></p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong>at </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> to </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong>on  </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> in</p>`],
    answer:3,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Giới từ</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>on the right side of st: ở bên phải của cái gì</p><p>The desk is opposite the bed and there is a closet <strong>(26) <u>on</u></strong> the right side of the room.</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Bàn làm việc đối diện giường ngủ và có tủ đựng quần áo bên phải phòng.</p><p><strong>Chọn C.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:27, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 27:</strong></p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong>large  </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> suitable </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> dangerous </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong>small</p>`],
    answer:4,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Từ vựng</p><p><strong>Giải thích:</strong></p><p>A. large (adj): rộng    </p><p>B. suitable (adj): phù hợp</p><p>C. dangerous (adj): nguy hiểm  </p>

<p>D. small (adj): nhỏ</p><p>The room is rather <strong>(27) <u>small</u></strong>, but it’s OK.</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Căn phòng khá nhỏ, nhưng nó ổn.</p><p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p><p><strong><u>Tạm dịch bài đọc:</u></strong></p><p style="text-align: justify;">Việt là sinh viên và anh ấy đang sống trong một căn phòng tại ngoại thành Hà Nội. Nó là một phần của ngôi nhà cũ. Anh ấy có một phòng và một nhà bếp và dùng chung phòng tắm với ba người khác. Trong phòng của anh ấy, có một cái giường ở phía bên tay trái. Có một chiếc ghế bành bên cạnh giường. Bàn làm việc đối diện giường ngủ và có tủ đựng quần áo bên phải phòng. Phía trên bàn làm việc có giá sách và phía trên giường có đồng hồ. Anh ấy có một chiếc TV và một băng cát-xét. Căn phòng khá nhỏ, nhưng nó ổn. Việt rất thích căn phòng này.</p>`

  },
  {id:28, 
    question: `<p><strong><em>Read the following passage and mark the letter A, B, C, or D on your answer sheet to indicate the correct answer to each of the questions.</em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Living in the country is something that people from the city often dream about. However, in reality, it has both advantages and disadvantages.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There are certainly many advantages to living in the country. First, you can enjoy peace and quietness. Moreover, people tend to be friendlier. A further advantage is that there is less traffic, so it is safer for young children.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">However, there are certain disadvantages or drawbacks to life outside the city. First, because there are fewer people, you are likely to have few friends. In addition, entertainment is difficult to find, particularly in the evening. Furthermore, the fact that there are fewer shops and services means that it is hard to find jobs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In short, it can be seen that the country is more suitable for some people than others. On the whole, it is often the best for those who are retired or who have young children. In contrast, young people who have a career are better provided in the city.</p>
<p><strong>Question 28:</strong> According to the passage, living in the country has ___________.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> only good points    </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> only bad points </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> both good and bad points  </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> no disadvantages</p>`],
    answer:3,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Đọc hiểu</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong>Theo đoạn văn, sống ở nông thôn có ___________.</p><p>A. chỉ điểm tốt</p><p>B. chỉ điểm xấu</p><p>C. cả điểm tốt và điểm xấu</p><p>D. không có nhược điểm</p><p><strong>Thông tin:</strong> However, in reality, it has both advantages and disadvantages.<strong></strong></p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Tuy nhiên, trong thực tế, nó có cả mặt lợi và mặt hại.</p><p><strong>Chọn C.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:29, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 29:</strong> How many advantages does living in the country have?</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> Two </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> Three   </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> Four </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> five</p>`],
    answer:2,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Đọc hiểu</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong>Sống ở nông thôn có bao nhiêu thuận lợi?</p><p>A. Hai  </p><p>B. Ba   </p>

<p>C. Bốn   </p><p>D. Năm</p><p><strong>Thông tin:</strong> There are certainly many advantages to living in the country. First, you can enjoy peace and quietness. Moreover, people tend to be friendlier. A further advantage is that there is less traffic, so it is safer for young children.<strong></strong></p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Chắc chắn có rất nhiều thuận lợi để sống ở nông thôn. Đầu tiên, bạn có thể tận hưởng sự yên bình và tĩnh lặng. Hơn nữa, mọi người có xu hướng thân thiện hơn. Một ưu điểm nữa là ít xe cộ qua lại nên an toàn hơn cho trẻ nhỏ.</p>

<p><strong>Chọn B.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:30, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 30:</strong> Living in the country is safer for young children because___________.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> there is less traffic </p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> there are fewer people</p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> there are few shops </p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> there are few services</p>`],
    answer:1,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Đọc hiểu</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong>Sống ở nông thôn an toàn hơn cho trẻ nhỏ vì ________.</p><p>A. có ít xe cộ hơn</p><p>B. có ít người hơn</p><p>C. có ít cửa hàng</p><p>D. có ít dịch vụ</p><p><strong>Thông tin:</strong> A further advantage is that there is less traffic, so it is safer for young children.<strong></strong></p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Một ưu điểm nữa là ít xe cộ qua lại nên an toàn hơn cho trẻ nhỏ.</p><p><strong>Chọn A.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:31, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 31:</strong> Which of the following statements is NOT true according to the passage?</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> People in the country tend to be friendlier than people in the city.</p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> It’s hard to find entertainment in the country.</p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> There are fewer shops and services in the country.</p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> The country is only suitable for retired people</p>`],
    answer:4,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Đọc hiểu</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong>Câu nào sau đây KHÔNG đúng theo đoạn văn?</p>

<p>A. Người dân ở nông thôn có xu hướng thân thiện hơn người ở thành phố.</p><p>B. Thật khó để tìm thấy chương trình giải trí ở nông thôn.</p><p>C. Ở nông thôn có ít cửa hàng và dịch vụ hơn.</p><p>D. Nông thôn chỉ phù hợp với những người đã nghỉ hưu</p><p><strong>Thông tin:</strong> On the whole, it is often the best for those who are retired or who have young children.<strong></strong></p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Nhìn chung, nó thường là tốt nhất cho những người đã nghỉ hưu hoặc những người có con nhỏ.</p>

<p><strong>Chọn D.</strong></p>`

  },
  {id:32, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 32:</strong> Having few friends is _______________________.</p>
    `, 
    options:[`<p><strong>A.</strong> one of drawbacks to life in the country</p>`, 
      `<p><strong>B.</strong> the only disadvantage to living in the country</p>`, 
      `<p><strong>C.</strong> one of certain drawbacks to life outside the city</p>`,
      `<p><strong>D.</strong> one of certain advantages to life outside the city</p>`],
    answer:3,
    explanation:`<p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Đọc hiểu</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong>Có ít bạn bè là _______________________.</p><p>A. một trong những hạn chế đối với cuộc sống ở nông thôn</p><p>B. bất lợi duy nhất để sống ở nông thôn</p><p>C. một trong những hạn chế nhất định đối với cuộc sống bên ngoài thành phố</p><p>D. một trong những lợi thế nhất định đối với cuộc sống bên ngoài thành phố</p><p><strong>Thông tin:</strong> However, there are certain disadvantages or drawbacks to life outside the city. First, because there are fewer people, you are likely to have few friends. <strong></strong></p>

<p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Tuy nhiên, cuộc sống bên ngoài thành phố cũng có những nhược điểm hoặc hạn chế nhất định. Thứ nhất, vì có ít người hơn, bạn có khả năng có ít bạn bè.</p><p><strong>Chọn C.</strong></p><p><strong><u>Tạm dịch bài đọc:</u></strong></p><p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Sống ở nông thôn là điều mà dân thành phố thường mơ ước. Tuy nhiên, trong thực tế, nó có cả mặt lợi và mặt hại.</em></p><p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Chắc chắn có rất nhiều thuận lợi để sống ở nông thôn. Đầu tiên, bạn có thể tận hưởng sự yên bình và tĩnh lặng. Hơn nữa, mọi người có xu hướng thân thiện hơn. Một ưu điểm nữa là ít xe cộ qua lại nên an toàn hơn cho trẻ nhỏ.</em></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Tuy nhiên, cuộc sống bên ngoài thành phố cũng có những nhược điểm hoặc hạn chế nhất định. Thứ nhất, vì có ít người hơn, bạn có khả năng có ít bạn bè. Ngoài ra, rất khó tìm thấy các hoạt động giải trí, đặc biệt là vào buổi tối. Hơn nữa, thực tế là có ít cửa hàng và dịch vụ hơn đồng nghĩa với việc khó tìm được việc làm.</em></p><p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Tóm lại, có thể thấy rằng nông thôn phù hợp với một số người hơn là tất cả mọi người. Nhìn chung, nó thường là tốt nhất cho những người đã nghỉ hưu hoặc những người có con nhỏ. Ngược lại, những người trẻ có sự nghiệp nên ở thành phố.</em></p>`

  },
  {id:33, 
    question: `<p><strong>II. WRITING: (2 points)</strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Finish the second sentence so that it has a similar meaning to the first one, beginning with the given words or using suggestions.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Question 33:</strong> I have never seen such beautiful pictures before.</p>
    `, 
    options:[],
    rewrite:`<p>=&gt; They are</p>`,
    answer:'the most beautiful pictures that I have ever seen.',
    explanation:`<p><strong>33.</strong></p><p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Thì hiện tại hoàn thành</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong></p><p>S + have/ has never + Ved/V3 + N + before.</p><p>= It is/ They are + the most adj/ adj-est + N + that + S + have/ has ever + Ved/V3.</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Tôi chưa từng thấy những bức tranh đẹp như vậy bao giờ.</p><p>= Chúng là những bức tranh đẹp nhất mà tôi từng thấy.</p><p><strong>Đáp án: </strong>the most beautiful pictures that I have ever seen.</p>`

  },
  {id:34, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 34:</strong> Why do some ethnic people build the communal house?</p>
    `, 
    options:[],
    rewrite:`<p>=&gt; What</p>`,
    answer:'do some ethnic people build the communal house for?',
    explanation:`<p><strong>34.</strong></p><p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Câu hỏi chỉ mục đích</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong></p><p>Why + V(trợ) + S + V(chính)? = What + V(trợ) + S + V(chính) + for?: Vì sao, Tại sao</p>

<p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Tại sao một số người dân tộc lại xây dựng nhà rông?</p><p>= Một số dân tộc dựng nhà rông để làm gì?</p><p><strong>Đáp án:</strong>do some ethnic people build the communal house for?</p>`

  },
  {id:35, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 35:</strong> Playing beach games is very interesting</p>
    `, 
    options:[],
    rewrite:`<p>=&gt; It is </p>`,
    answer:'very interesting to play beach games.',
    explanation:`<p><strong>35.</strong></p><p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Cấu câu thông dụng</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong></p><p>Ving + is + adj. = It is + adj + to V.: Thấy như thế nào khi làm gì.</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Chơi trò chơi bãi biển rất thú vị.</p><p><strong>Đáp án:</strong><u>very interesting to play beach games.</u></p>`

  },
  {id:36, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 36:</strong> I get a lot of pleasure from reading cookery books.</p>
    `, 
    options:[],
    rewrite:`<p>=&gt;I enjoy</p>`,
    answer:'reading cookery books.',
    explanation:`<p><strong>36.</strong></p><p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Cụm từ đồng nghĩa</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong></p>

<p>get a lot of pleasure = enjoy: thích</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Tôi nhận được rất nhiều niềm vui từ việc đọc sách nấu ăn.</p><p>= Tôi thích đọc sách nấu ăn.</p><p><strong>Đáp án: </strong>reading cookery books.</p>`

  },
  {id:37, 
    question: `<p><strong><em></em></strong><strong><em>Write new sentences as similar as possible in meaning to the original sentences, using the given words in brackets. Do not change the given words in any ways.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Question 37:</strong> The worker is clever. He can make fine things from wood. (ENOUGH)</p>
    `, 
    options:[],
    rewrite:`<p>=&gt; </p>`,
    answer:'The worker is clever enough to make fine things from wood.',
    explanation:`<p><strong>37.</strong></p><p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>Mệnh đề<strong> </strong>nguyên nhân - kết quả</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong></p><p>Công thức với “enough”: S + to be + adj enough + to V.: đủ như thế nào để làm gì</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Người thợ khéo léo. Anh ấy có thể làm ra nhiều đồ đẹp từ gỗ.</p><p>= Người thợ đủ khéo léo để làm ra những món đồ tốt từ gỗ.</p>

<p><strong>Đáp án: </strong>The worker is clever enough to make fine things from wood.</p>`

  },
  {id:38, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 38:</strong> My father’s explanation about the subject was clearer than my brother’s. (CLEARLY)</p>
    `, 
    options:[],
    rewrite:`<p>=&gt; </p>`,
    answer:'My father explained the subject more clearly than my brother did.',
    explanation:`<p><strong>38.</strong></p><p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>So sánh hơn</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong></p><p>So sánh hơn với trạng từ: S + V + more adv + than S1 + V(trợ).</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Lời giải thích của cha tôi về chủ đề này rõ ràng hơn lời giải thích của anh tôi.</p><p>= Cha tôi giải thích chủ đề rõ ràng hơn anh tôi đã giải thích.</p><p><strong>Đáp án: </strong>My father explained the subject more clearly than my brother did.</p>`

  },
  {id:39, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 39:</strong> I lived on the farm with my grandma ten years ago. (USED)</p>
    `, 
    options:[],
    rewrite:`<p>=&gt; </p>`,
    answer:'I used to live on the farm with my grandma ten years ago.',
    explanation:`<p><strong>39.</strong></p><p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>to V/ Ving</p>

<p><strong>Giải thích: </strong></p><p>used to V: đã từng làm gì (chỉ thói quen trong quá khứ)</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Tôi đã sống trong trang trại với bà của tôi mười năm trước.</p><p><strong>Đáp án: </strong>I used to live on the farm with my grandma ten years ago.</p>`

  },
  {
    id:40, 
    question: `<p><strong>Question 40:</strong> He uses all of his free time to collect stamps. (SPENDS)</p>
    `, 
    options:[],
    rewrite:`<p>=&gt; </p>`,
    answer:'He spends all of his free time collecting stamps.',
    explanation:`<p><strong>40.</strong></p><p><strong>Kiến thức: </strong>to V/ Ving</p><p><strong>Giải thích: </strong></p><p>spend + thời gian + Ving: dành thời gian để làm gì</p><p>to V: để làm gì (chỉ mục đích)</p><p><strong>Tạm dịch: </strong>Anh ấy sử dụng tất cả thời gian rảnh rỗi của mình để sưu tập tem.</p><p>= Anh ấy dành tất cả thời gian rảnh để sưu tập tem.</p><p><strong>Đáp án:</strong>He spends all of his free time collecting stamps.</p> `
  }
   

  ];